[Music]
Hey, hey,
hey. Well, um, thank you so much for for
for jumping on the chat. Um, I'm really
excited about this, uh, this this talk.
Like, I used to work for Glovo, which
delivery hero has bought. uh and uh I
remember the engineering team spoke very
highly of the delivery here uh
engineering team. So really cool to to
to speak and hear uh your session today
Andre. So with that said I'll just give
it over to you.
Thank you. And as it already said I am
Andre I am a principal engineer and
delivery hero and if you would have any
questions you can easily contact me on
any of these. uh social networks and ask
your questions or just connect say hi.
So let's get started. Uh in delivery
hero today we deliver more than 10
million orders per day and we do this in
70 plus countries. We do this worldwide.
We do this 27 uh 24 per seven and it
wasn't been like this in 2020.
uh because when corona breakout happened
we grew exponentially and we were not
ready for this and we had a lot of
incidents
uh which were related to our unability
to scale and back then like five years
ago our uh CTO created this so call it
relability manifesto it's public in the
internet you can easily find it and one
like bullet point of this manifesto
store is called it we design for
failure. It has multiple uh mechanism
but one of them is exactly load testing.
the topic I'm going to talk about today
and if you look at this uh you will find
out that uh what actually we aim during
load testing we want for uh first of all
to test if we can scale uh rapidly to 3x
compared to our production load or to 4x
during a longer period of time we want
to run it more frequent this uh slide is
a bit outdated Uh currently we have
different requirements but this like uh
just for your understanding what we
wanted and we also want to know to have
realistic uh patterns of our operations.
We want to test uh in production and we
pass low test only if uh our latency is
under some specific thresholds and error
rate as well. So back then five years
ago it was completely manual process and
behind the gopher you can see the list
of uh pages report generated by humans
and uh like it was 12 pages of Google
doc uh with 20 30 screenshots from
different sources from data dog from
graphana from uh cloudatch and AWS and
it was only one uh lot test run for one
service. Back then we were doing this uh
on bi-weekly frequencies but right now
we should do this uh every week and you
can imagine uh it's not scalable doing
this manually and right now in my drive
we have 26 services. So you can imagine
the amount of work needs to be done by
either engineer and yeah so we decided
manual doesn't work and we embrace it
automation and our automation was
achieved with uh templating it was done
in goal and can you can see uh we have
someh placeholders and in this
placeholders you can either embed some
uh already predefined data for example
just date of the law test or you can
query our different data sources and in
this case we query Graphana cloud we get
some information about most about the
country with most load we have in
production and then we extract this
information and we can add it to the
document and then we can extract
throughput then we query load test and
then we can you know to uh calculate and
do some nice things it's not only data
but we also can draw some charts in our
docu comments and so on so forth. And
most important part of any of our law
test result is conclusion and uh like
even until months or two months ago
conclusions were looking like this. So
we just uh taking numbers from low test
from production we dividing and then we
say okay this is our multiplier and
almost that's all the same for uh error
rate. So we just calculate and say okay
our error rate was below
2%. And uh despite the report itself we
have reporting. So we report our results
to different our systems for our CTO for
our
directors vice presidents for all our
many people and to do this evaluation we
again we just compare if it's greater or
less than some number. So it's very dumb
but it works. But uh is this a
masterpiece we created? I can say like
five years ago yes it was a masterpiece
but uh technology doesn't stay still.
Technology evolves and uh rather than
you know just to run from technology we
decided to embrace it and use AI and I
can clearly tell you using AI is easy.
These three lines of code is almost all
um implementation we have and uh yeah
three lines of code it's easy but then
we have challenges because this three
lines of code doesn't do magic you can
call your AI model you can uh get some
results but to do this you need to
prepare a prompt so you need to write a
huge message the the t details
describing AI what you want from it and
the problem is that results inconsistent
even you have the same prompt you run it
multiple times results will be different
because uh and results will be different
between models between runs and results
will degrade over time and I'm not
talking only about the cases when you
have long conversation with AI I mean
this is known uh issue so
Because when you have longer
conversation, you're
uh using this context window too much
and maybe I start to forget something,
mixing
something. In case we face it, it was
actually um we creating a chat a thread
with AI every time a new one we just
sent. Please this is our information.
please
uh do some evolation based on this
information and after one week or two
weeks of using it changes you know
drastically uh the output so sometimes
it's very complicated you need always to
adjust your prompt
um what else you have unavoidable
limitations I already mentioned this
context window so it's limited uh you
can't throw everything you have uh to AI
and expect it solve all your problems.
Another problem hallucinations and my
favorite AI are talkative. They really
like to write you a bunch of data uh you
didn't ask them about this and even if
you specify something saying oh please
uh give me only one number you will get
this number but it will be surrounded by
multiple paragraph of the text. So to
address some of these
um problems what we decided we decided
to split our prompt into three parts.
First part is a definition and
requirements. This is the same
definition and requirements we have in
our relability manifesto. Right now we
call it engineering manifesto about load
testing. What uh multiplier do we expect
from the our lo test? What our uh
thresholds for error rate? what our
thresholds for latency
u what the frequency of our load is we
give all this information to AI and then
uh we provide a list of data and data
consist of also to part so we give the
production data because AI needs to
compare with something so we can say
okay this is our production results and
based on this please uh calculate what
should be our multiplier what should be
expected load from our uh load test and
then we provide actually load test data.
So almost the same as production but uh
with more details I would say and then
we have a most important part this is
setup of response as I already mentioned
AI is very talkative AI is hallucinating
so we need to set up it uh what we
actually expect and in which format and
this is very sensitive part any word to
change here changes completely results
AI gives you so
Talking about definitions and
requirements as I already mentioned this
is our uh real requirements about what
is load test and they already mentioned
like scalability how many requests per
uh minute or per second we expect so we
expect for one minute rapid uh increase
up to 2x and so on so forth. So we give
all of this information we give
information about our SLOs about our
error rate and then second part uh
actual data uh and uh what data we for
example u from production we get
throughput so we need a know what is our
current throughput and uh yeah and then
endpoints metadatas this one we using
for for AI try to understand uh the
quality of our law test. As I already
mentioned uh our law
test should uh test realistic scenarios
not just hitting health and point one
million times. This will work for sure
but uh it should be realistic. So we say
which exactly end point use it uh in the
production and then uh we provide lotus
data. So we give data about our memory
consumption, CPU consumption, the
latency we have during the load test,
the error rate, the throughput we have
and again in placement of data use it
during this load test. And as I
mentioned this is the third part. This
is very important one. The most
important one because depends on how you
specify this you will give result. Uh
this very simplify this is not actual
what we were using but this to
understand you uh what we request. So
for example we say uh in our data we
provide timestamps in the uni apo and AI
will use it in you know um uh result
output just printing these numbers
everywhere and this then we say oh
please translate it to UTC format uh
human readable because we don't
understand these numbers we need some
more
uh more understandable
uh time uh stamps and then we say uh
this is my favorite uh
please write a number and then add your
explanation. Why it's very important?
Because when you read multiple uh
reports every day uh the most important
information you want to get uh is like
what is multiplier, what is error rate,
what is latency and you want to find it
in some specific place. You don't want
to read hundreds of pages of document
just to find one number. You want to
know to know on which page you will find
this information and in which format it
will be. So then we say okay please
provide this information about
multiplier about error rate throughput
uh latency any anomalies and quality of
the tests and give you recommendations
if you have any. And this is example
response. I mean as I mentioned is
talkative and uh I'm asking please give
me a number and it doesn't give a number
provides a huge
um recommendation about what is going
but it's very good actually if you read
it it's super good because it uh tells
you what happened what was ramp ups in
your law
test is it actually aligned with our uh
principles from the relability manifest
test and so on and so forth. So
u this the same about error rate it says
okay it's under our expectation because
it's very very small one uh about
throughput it says okay but in load test
you didn't reach your uh multiplier of
the lo test so you need to improve you
need to get more load response time in
our uh relation manifest we don't
specify what expected uh from our uh
latency from our services but then it
says okay it's under like 500
milliseconds and it's should be
fine and uh so on so forth and uh in the
end it gives some summary and if you
check uh it says I couldn't give you any
recommendations about CPU and memory
because you didn't provide us
information about CPU and memory and
this was from the previous runs and then
we added the information about memory
and CPU and uh actually we broke
everything. Uh what if and out using AI
uh every time you modify your prompt you
should expect
unexpected and the problem of this
because like uh you have this
unavoidable limitations unfortunately
and if you look at this um uh this is
representation of data we generate
during the load test. This is uh you see
a lot of data points, a lot of ports.
This is another one. And if you look uh
uh the example from the uh above it
represents only 150 ports. But in our
usual law test when we generate real uh
multiplier load,
it's,500. So when we generate this and
when we fit all of this information to
AI, this is hundreds of thousand of
numbers. AI sometimes can't deal with
because doesn't understand and I believe
at some point we just reached this uh
context window of information we can fit
to AI and it just you know started to
pick information randomly but what we
did uh you need to structure your prompt
better and you need to cut some data and
we did after we removed some uh after we
structured better our prompt and
provided better information about what
is the actual CPU consumption, what is
the uh per port for example. Uh so AI
started to give us very good uh
suggestions. it can clearly uh find out
laners uh in our CPU um consumption and
one of uh actually suggestion was oh
maybe you have a problem with load
balancer because definitely some of your
ports receiving more u load than it
expected and yeah I mean it is true this
is something we need to check so
conclusion AI uh starting AI is very
easy as I mentioned It's only three
lines of code. Uh it is helpful tool
when you know how to formulate your
request properly but it might be
unhelpful if you don't know how to
formulate it
properly. And yeah uh we are hiring if
you want to solve complex problems also
related to AI please uh go ahead and uh
join us. And yeah, again, if you still
have any questions, I'm please contact
me on any of these social networks. I'm
open to answer anything. Thank you.
Thank you so much uh Andrea for this
wonderful chat. Uh love the
presentation. Like I I I think you're
probably a master coder and a slide
designer at least in another life. Um,
so we do have one minute uh left, but uh
the community has asked quite a bit of
questions. So I'm going to pick
um one. So can AI help? Oh, I think this
one was answered by the community. Um
well, somebody asked in the in the chat
in your presentation if you've tried
like structured outputs and did they
help or hinder
Oh yes as I said in the third part we
try to ask AI to structure output and
sometimes it helps sometimes not when
it's very depend because even generating
the uh data from um our law test you
don't generate the same data every time
it's very different because you have
different
uh time frame when you load lot test you
have different results of lotus and AI
interpreted it very differently
So sometimes it's complicated to do
this, but yeah, I believe we can uh nail
it down at some point. Nice. Well, um I
appreciate the cander and um one thing I
do want to mention uh so delivery hero
is definitely like by the way they
haven't paid me to say that. Delivery
Hero is definitely like a very very cool
place to work at. Uh like I used to work
at a place that a delivery herobot and
um I think if you're an engineer right
now listening to this chat like
definitely go check it out like um yeah
really really uh exciting place uh to to
to build software. Now we are getting
close to the end of our first half so I
just want to say a massive thank you
Andre for uh coming on uh to this
conference. Really really enjoyed the
session. So thank you. Yeah. Thank you.
from Vegas.